Yulia Afletunova

Data Analyst Germany, Europe (with work permit)

■ afletunova.yulia@gmail.com

in afletunova

• afletunova

ABOUT

10435 Berlin

Data Analyst with over 5 years of experience in data science, data analytics, data engineering, and product analytics. I have provided actionable insights for a Big Tech (Yandex), managing over 10,000 metrics, and an EdTech startup (MEL Science), where I served as the primary decision-maker in analytics. I value learning and knowledge sharing and am the founder of the Analyst Girls Club, a community for women in the field.

EXPERIENCE

• Data Analyst (Analyst-Developer) @ Yandex ('Russia's Google).

Apr 2023 - Feb 2024

Remote

- Analysed multivariate Big Data A/B tests on SERP to confirm the outcome of experiments, interpreting over 1000 metrics.
- Analysed A/B testing experiments, delivering results in BI dashboards, presentations, and generating 10+ detailed reports to let stakeholders gain insights and make informed decisions.
- Calculated metric sensitivity, based on experimental data from 40+ A/B tests, using No-code ML pipelines to improve data analysis accuracy.

Python YQL YTsaurus DataLens (Tableau or Looker-like Data Visualization tool) Business Intelligence

- Full-Stack Data Analyst (Analytics Engineer) @ 3commas.io (a cryptocurrency trading platform). Nov 2022 - Jan 2023 Georgia, Tbilisi
 - Implemented data integrations with third-party services APIs, designing data models, utilized by 12+ analysts across multiple departments for data validation.
 - Facilitated the team of analysts, conducting ETL data processing and storage workflows using Airflow/Redshift pipelines.
 - Implemented code-style rules and best advanced SQL and practices for **git-based development**, improving collaboration and efficiency within the team of 12 data analysts.
 - Transformed business requirements into data requirements to improve the core DWH, including DBT models. SQL AWS Redshift Airflow Python DBT
- Data Scientist @ MEL Science (an international edTech).

Sep 2019 - Sep 2022

Russia, Saint Petersburg; Armenia, Yerevan

- Maintained a consistent retention rate of the monthly subscription model at the 90% level throughout 3 years by monitoring churn and other key metrics.
- Delivered insights with each fluctuation and prevented potential annual losses of up to \$200,000 per insight.
- Applied statistical survival analysis techniques with prediction to improve production estimates, achieving a 15% reduction in stock storage costs.
- Collaborated with 5 product teams, delivering insights and crafting ad-hoc queries.
- Analyzed A/B tests to improve conversion rates, leading to a notable 2-3\% increase.
- Prepared data and 5 reports on average for monthly and annual **reporting to stakeholders**.
- Conducted a data analysis course for 10+ product stakeholders to enhance the team's data analysis skills.
- Mentored two analysts individually at different times, guiding professional development and enhancing financial and marketing analysis expertise.

Python Jupyter PostgreSQL DBT Metabase Mixpanel Microsoft Excel Data Visualization

• Data Scientist @ AppliedML (outsource AI-startup)

Mar 2019 - Aug 2019 Russia, Saint-Petersburg

• Product Owner @ MotionLearning (App for creating AI-generated educational video content).

Aug 2018 - Feb 2019

Russia, Saint-Petersburg

EDUCATION

• Bachelor of Computer Science @ Saint Petersburg State University, Saint Petersburg, Russia

Sep 2015 - Jul 2019

Additional Experience

• Founder @ Analyst Girls Club (female-only professional community)

Sep 2021 - Present

- Established a safe and supportive environment for more than 200 women from diverse backgrounds to excel in a career.
- Operated networking events, enabling members to forge meaningful connections, exchange ideas, and share unique experiences within a supportive and understanding community.
- Empowered women in data, system, and business analysis, promoting inclusivity and gender diversity within the industry.